In this video, we're gonna continue our discussion of parsing with the idea of a
在这段视频中，我们将继续讨论使用
derivation. So a derivation is a sequence of productions so beginning with the start
派生。所以派生是一系列的产品，所以从开始开始
symbol, we can apply productions one at a time. In sequence and that produces a
符号，我们可以一次应用一个产品。，这会产生一个
derivation. And a derivation can be drawn in a different way instead of as a linear
派生。并且可以用不同的方式绘制派生，而不是将其绘制为线性
sequence of replacements, we can draw it as a tree. So for example, if I have a
替换序列，我们可以把它画成一棵树。例如，如果我有一个
nonterminal x it appears in a derivation, then when I replace x, I can represent
非端点x，它出现在派生中，那么当我替换x时，我可以表示
that by making the children Of x, the left hand side of the rule that I used to
通过将x的子代设为我以前使用的规则的左手边
replace x. So I applied production x goes to y1 to yn, I add the y1 to yn is
替换x，所以我把x的乘积应用到y1到yn，我把y1加到yn是
children of x in the tree that I'm building up. Let's do an example. Here is
我正在建造的那棵树上有x的孩子。让我们举个例子。这就是
our simple grammar of arithmetic expressions and let's consider this
我们简单的算术表达式语法，让我们考虑一下
particular string id id + id. So what we're going to do now is we're going to
特定字符串id+id。所以我们现在要做的是
parse this string and we're going to show how to produce a derivation for the string
解析该字符串，我们将展示如何生成该字符串的派生
and also at the same time build the tree. And here it is, Over here, there is
同时也在建造这棵树。这就是了，在这里，这就是
derivation beginning in e and ending in the string that we're interested in with
从e开始，以我们感兴趣的字符串结束的派生
one production applied each step along the way and here is the corresponding tree and
在此过程中，每一步都应用了一个产品，下面是相应的树和
this is called a parse tree. This is a parse tree of this expression or this
这称为解析树。这是此表达式或此表达式的分析树
input string. So let's walk through this derivation in detail. The right side in
输入字符串。所以让我们详细介绍一下这个推导过程。中的右侧
red, we're going to have the tree that we're building up. And on the left side in
瑞德，我们将有一棵我们正在建造的树。在左边的
blue, we're going to have the steps in the derivation that we've taken so far. So
蓝色，我们将会有我们到目前为止所做的推导中的步骤。所以
initially, our derivation consists of just the start symbol e and our tree consists
最初，我们的派生只由开始符号e组成，而我们的树由
of just the root which is also the start symbol. So the first step is that we have
也就是开始符号的根。所以第一步是我们有
a production e goes to e + e and what that means is over on the tree, we take the
乘积e转到e+e，这意味着在树上，我们取
root of the tree and we make, we give it three children e + ne. So now, we replace
树根，我们做，我们给它三个孩子e+ne。所以现在，我们把
the first t by e z. We use the production e goes to e z and that means
第一个t by e z，我们用乘积e到e z，这意味着
we take the first e in the tree and we give it to three children, e
我们把树上的第一个e送给三个孩子，e
[inaudible]. Continuing along we take the fi rst e here that remains in this
[听不见]。继续往前走，我们走这里的第一条路，那就是留在这里的第一条路。
expression and we replace it by id which means we make id a child of the left most
表达式，我们将其替换为id，这意味着我们将id设为最左边的子级。
e in the tree that we're building. And then we replace the second e by id using
E在我们正在建造的树上。然后我们用id替换第二个e，使用
the production e goes to id and finally, we use the same thing with the third e and
乘积e转到id，最后，我们对第三个e使用相同的东西，
now, we have completed our Parse Tree. So here again, from the start symbol to the
现在，我们已经完成了我们的解析树。所以这里再一次，从开始符号到
string, we were interested in parsing and in the process we built up this Parse Tree
字符串，我们对解析很感兴趣，在这个过程中我们构建了这个解析树
of the expression. Now there are lots of interesting things to say about parse
表达式的。现在关于解析有很多有趣的事情要说
trees. So first of all, parse trees have terminals at the leaves and nonterminals
树木。因此，首先，解析树在叶子和非终结点都有终结点
at the interior nodes and furthermore, in-order traversal of the leaves is the
在内部节点处，此外，叶的顺序遍历是
original input. So let's back up and look at our example and confirm all this. If we
原始输入。因此，让我们回顾一下我们的示例，并确认所有这些。如果我们
look at the leaves, we can see that they are all terminals, Okay? And the interior
看看树叶，我们可以看到它们都是终端，好吗？以及内部
nodes are all nonterminals. In this case, it's only one nonterminal in our language,
节点都是非终结点。在这种情况下，它在我们的语言中只有一个非终结符，
all the interior nodes are e and the leaves are the terminals of the string.
所有内部节点都是e，叶子是字符串的末端。
And then we can see if we do an inward reversal of the leaves, we get exactly
然后我们可以看到，如果我们将树叶向内翻转，我们就会得到
this input string that we started with. Furthermore, the Parse Tree shows the
我们开始时使用的这个输入字符串。此外，解析树显示了
association of the operations and the input string does not. So you may notice
操作和输入字符串的关联不会。所以你可能会注意到
here that the way that this Parse Tree is constructed, the times binds more tightly
在这里，这棵解析树的构建方式将时间更紧密地捆绑在一起
than the plus because the times is a sub-tree. Of the tree containing plus. And
因为《泰晤士报》是一棵子树。包含加号的树的。和
so this means that we would do the e e first before we would add e and some, some
所以这意味着我们会先做e，然后再加e和一些，一些
of you may have wondered well, how did I know. To pick this Parse Tree because
你们中的一些人可能想知道，我是怎么知道的。选择此解析树是因为
actually if you think about it, there's another derivation. Actually there are
实际上，如果你仔细想想，还有另一种推导。实际上有
several derivations that will give me a different Parse Tree where the plus, where
几个派生，它们将给我一个不同的解析树，加号和位置
the times is towards the root and the plus is nested inside the times. So let's not
Times指向根，加号嵌套在Times中。所以我们不要
worry about that for right now, and let's just say that somehow we knew that this
现在先担心这个问题，我们只能说，不知何故，我们知道这一点
was the Parse Tree we wanted and I gave you a derivation that produces that Parse
是我们想要的解析树，我给了您一个派生来生成该解析
Tree. Continuing on, the previous derivation I showed you is actually a very
树。继续，我给你们展示的前一个派生实际上是一个非常
special derivation. It's what's called a leftmost derivation where each step will
特殊派生。这就是所谓的最左边的派生，每一步
replace the leftmost nonterminal in our string of terminals and nonterminals. And
替换我们的终结符和非终结符字符串中最左边的非终结符。和
there's a natural and equivalent notion of a rightmost derivation and here it is.
最右边的派生有一个自然而等价的概念，这就是它。
Here is a rightmost derivation for the same string. Again, beginning with the
下面是同一字符串最右侧的派生结果。同样，从
start symbol ending with a string we're interested in. And notice that at each
开始符号以我们感兴趣的字符串结尾。请注意，在每个
step, we're replacing the rightmost non-terminal. So here, we replace the only
步骤，我们要替换最右边的非终结点。所以在这里，我们用唯一的
non-terminal e and we get e + c. And then in the second step, we replace the second
非末尾e，我们得到e+c，然后在第二步，我们替换第二个
non-terminal e with id and so on for the rest of the string. So let's just
非终结符e带有id，依此类推，用于睡觉的字符串。所以让我们就这样
illustrate this entirely with our little picture here of the tree and the
完全用我们这里的树和树的小图片来说明这一点
derivation simultaneously so once again over here is our tree and this is the
同时派生所以这里再一次是我们的树，这是
root, the start symbol e and, and in blue is our derivation so we begin by replacing
根，开始符号e和，蓝色是我们的派生，所以我们从替换
e by e + e. That's the only nonterminal so it's the rightmost one and then working
乘以e+e，这是唯一的非终结符，所以它是最右边的，然后就可以工作了
from the right side of the tree, we replace the right e by id and then the
在树的右侧，我们用id替换右边的e，然后用
left id gets replaced by e z. And now the right most e that remains is replaced
左边的id被替换为e z，现在剩下的最右边的e被替换
by id and finally the only e that remains is also replaced by id. Now I want to
通过id，最后剩下的唯一e也被id替换。现在我想要
point out that the rightmost and leftmost derivations I showed you have exactly the
指出我向您展示的最右边和最左边的派生恰好具有
same Parse Tree. And, this was not an accident. Every Parse Tree has a rightmost
相同的解析树。而且，这不是意外。每个解析树都有一个最右边的
and a leftmost derivation. It's just about the order in which the branches are added.
和最左边的派生。这只是关于添加分支的顺序。
So for example, if I have the first production e goes to e + e, now I have a
例如，如果我有第一个乘积e转到e+e，现在我有一个
choice on how to build my tree. I can either work on. This sub-tree or I can
关于如何建造我的树的选择。我要么继续工作。这棵子树或者我可以
work on that sub-tree. And if I build this one first, that will be a rightmost
在那棵子树上工作。如果我先建造这个，那将是最右边的
derivation. If I continue to always work on the rightmost non-terminal of course,
派生。当然，如果我总是在最右边的非终端上工作，
And if I work on this one first, I can use that to do a leftmost derivation. Now it's
如果我先做这个，我可以用它来做最左边的推导。现在它是
important also to realize that there are many derivations besides rightmost and
同样重要的是要认识到，除了最右边的和之外，还有许多派生
leftmost. I could, I could choose non-terminals in some random order to do
最左边。我可以，我可以随机选择非终结点来做
my replacements. But th e rightmost and leftmost ones are the ones that we're most
我的接班人。但是最右边和最左边的是我们最
concerned with.
关心的是。